Guide to the Sarah Brown Ingersoll Cooper Papers, 1813-1921
Cooper, Sarah Brown Ingersoll Papers, 1813-1921
- Series II. Writings
  - The Bankrupt's Daughter
    - Chapter 41 (Box 7, Folder 71)
    - Chapter 42 (Box 7, Folder 72)
  - Essays, Articles, and Speeches
    - School Compositions 1844-1849 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - School Compositions 1850-1854 (Box 10, Folder 40)
    - Miscellaneous 1880-1889 (Box 10, Folder 46)
    - Miscellaneous 1890-1895 (Box 10, Folder 47)
    - Address to Howard Literary Society (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Address to the Philomathean Society (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - An Advertisement for Every Season (Box 10, Folder 41)
    - Are Laws Favorable or Unfavorable to Women? (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Character Building (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Forward or Backward - Which? (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Helps and Hindrances to Practical Christian Work (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Organized Charities (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Poems (Box 10, Folder 42)
    - Practical Ethics for the Home and Government (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Press Club Address (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Professor McGrew (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Set Out in Life with Some Purpose (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Social Hygiene (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - The Discipline of Suffering (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - The Race for Wealth (Box 10, Folder 43)
    - Visions of the Unseen (Box 10, Folder 44)
    - Why I Believe in Woman Suffrage (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Woman in Education - Her Work in the Kindergarten Department (Box 10, Folder 45)
    - Woman in Religious Teaching and Work (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Woman's Work in Church (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Women as Teachers in the Congregational Church (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Women's Clubs (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Miscellany (Box 9, Folder 19)
- Series III. Education
  - Bible Class
    - Bible Class Lessons: Feb. 1877 - Feb. 1883 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Bible Class Notes 1877-1896 (Box 13, Folder 35)
    - Bible Class Material 1878-1880 (Box 13, Folder 36)
    - Ladies Bible Class list of students, 1881 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Letter of appreciation to Sarah Cooper from Calvary Presbyterian Church, 1881 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Bible Class Lessons: Mar. 1883 -Sept. 1884 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Bible Class Lessons: Nov. 1884-July 1886 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Bible Class Lessons: Oct. 1886-Mar. 1887 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Bible Class Lessons: Apr. 1887-July 1888 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Bible Class Lessons: July 1888-Sept. 1890 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Bible Class Lessons: Oct. 1890-Nov. 1891 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Bible Class Lessons: Nov. 1891-Oct. 1982 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Bible Class Lessons: Jan. 1893-Sept. 1895 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Letters from the Congregational Sunday-School and Publishing Society 1894 (Box 13, Folder 41)
    - Bible Class Lessons: July 1896-Sept. 1896 (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Bible Class Material, undated (Box 13, Folder 37)
    - Bible Class Material, undated (Box 13, Folder 38)
    - Essay by Sarah Cooper about her Bible Class teaching methods, undated (Box 13, Folder 42)
    - Notebook with notes for Bible Classes, undated (Box 13, Folder 39)
    - Student Essay from Bible Class, undated (Box 13, Folder 40)
    - The King and His Kingdom and the Church Catechism, book 1 (Box 13, Folder 43)
  - Kindergartens
    - Jackson Street Free Kindergarten Benefit Programme, Nov. 1880 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Jackson Street Free Kindergarten Association Annual Report, 1880 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Jackson Street Free Kindergarten Association Annual Report, 1881 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - The Pacific School Journal - "The Kindergarten, by Sarah B. Cooper, in The Pacfic School Journal, 1882 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Jackson Street Free Kindergarten Association Annual Report, 1882 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Christmas and the Kindergarten, by Sarah Cooper, 1882 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Jackson Street Free Kindergarten Association Annual Report, 1883 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - The California Teacher and Home Journal, Mar. 1884 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Golden Gate Kindergarten Association Fifth Annual Report, 1884 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Lecture announcement for Miss Emily Faithfull, 1884 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Golden Gate Kindergarten Association Fifth Annual Report material, 1884 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - The Kindergarten as a Preventitive of Crime, 1885 (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Golden Gate Kindergarten Association Sixth Annual Report, 1885 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Welcome Program for the Stanford Kindergarten, 1886 (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - Golden Gate Kindergarten Association Seventh Annual Report, 1886 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Golden Gate Kindergarten Association Eighth Annual Report, 1887 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Subjects for Daily Meditation and Prayer, prepared by Mrs. Leland Stanford, 1887 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - The Kindergarten, May 1888 (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - Golden Gate Kindergarten Association Ninth Annual Report, 1888 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Free Kindergartens - Practical Results of Ten Year's Work, by Sarah B. Cooper, 1889 (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - Golden Gate Kindergarten Association Tenth Annual Report, 1889 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - The Kindergarten, May 1890 (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - Golden Gate Kindergarten Association Eleventh Annual Report, 1890 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - The California Educational Review, Jan. 1891, Feb. 1891, Apr.1891 (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - Letter to Sarah Cooper about kindergarten being named in her honor, May 1891 (Box 8, Folder 34)
    - American Teacher, June 1891 (Box 8, Folder 35)
    - Golden Gate Kindergarten Association Twelfth Annual Report, 1891 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Golden Gate Kindergarten Association Treasurer's Report, 1891 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Golden Gate Kindergarten Twelfth Annual Report - manuscript copy and notes, 1891 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Golden Gate Kindergarten Twelfth Annual Report - manuscript copy and notes, 1891 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Golden Gate Kindergarten Twelfth Annual Report - manuscript copy and notes, 1891 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Golden Gate Kindergarten Twelfth Annual Report - manuscript copy, 1891 (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Golden Gate Kindergarten Twelfth Annual Report - typescript fragments, 1891 (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - Golden Gate Kindergarten Association Annual Report subscriber list, 1891 (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Golden Gate Kindergarten Training School Graduating Exercises, May 1892 (Box 8, Folder 36)
    - The Kindergarten News, Aug. 1892-Sept. 1892 (Box 8, Folder 37)
    - Golden Gate Kindergarten Association Thirteenth Annual Report, 1892 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Golden Gate Kindergarten Association Thirteenth Annual Report fragments, 1892 (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - The Pacific Coast Teacher, Mar. 1893 (Box 8, Folder 38)
    - Golden Gate Kindergarten Association Fourteenth Annual Report, 1893 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Symmetrical Outlines of Development and Training for the Golden Gate Kindergarten Association, by Professor C.H. McGrew, 1893 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - The Kindergarten: Its Aims and Methods, 1893 (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - California School of Methods for Teachers and Kindergartners - Commencement Exercises, June 1894 (Box 8, Folder 39)
    - Mrs. Sarah B. Cooper, First President International Kindergarten Union, 1894 (Box 8, Folder 40)
    - Golden Gate Kindergarten Association Fifteenth Annual Report, 1894 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Golden Gate Kindergarten Association Fifteenth Annual Report - manuscript copy, 1894 (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - Golden Gate Kindergarten Association Sixteenth Annual Report, 1895 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Golden Gate Kindergarten Association Sixteenth Annual Report - manuscript copy, 1895 (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - The Review of Reviews, 1896 (Box 8, Folder 41)
    - Golden Gate Kindergarten Association Seventeenth Annual Report - manuscript copy and notes, 1896 (Box 10, Folder 33)
    - Golden Gate Kindergarten Association, 2 manuscript pages about organization, 1896 (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - Kindergarten News -The Life and Death of Mrs. Cooper, Jan. 1897 (Box 8, Folder 42)
    - Kindergarten Magazine - Frontispiece by Sarah B. Cooper, Feb. 1897 (Box 8, Folder 43)
    - Golden Gate Kindergarten Association Eighteenth Annual Report, 1897 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Golden Gate Kindergarten Association Financial Statement 1898 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Golden Gate Kindergarten Association Twentieth Annual Report, 1899 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Golden Gate Kindergarten Association Twenty-first Annual Report, 1900 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Golden Gate Kindergarten Association Twenty-fourth Annual Report, 1903 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Golden Gate Kindergarten Association Financial Statement 1904 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Golden Gate Kindergarten Association Twenty-sixth Annual Report, 1905 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Golden Gate Kindergarten Association Twenty-seventh Annual Report, 1906 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - A Kindergarten Song by Isabel Darling (Box 8, Folder 44)
    - Address on Kindergartens (Box 8, Folder 45)
    - Address to Children (Box 8, Folder 46)
    - Every Mother a Kindergartner (Box 8, Folder 47)
    - History of Kindergartens in San Francisco (Box 8, Folder 48)
    - International Kindergarten Union Information Pamphlet (Box 8, Folder 49)
    - Sarah Cooper's Address to the graduates of Kindergarten Training School (Box 8, Folder 50)
    - Shall the Kindergarten be a Part of the Public School System of the State? (Box 8, Folder 51)
    - The Influence of the Kindergarten on Primary and Higher Education (Box 8, Folder 52)
    - The Kindergarten as a Character Builder (Box 8, Folder 53)
    - The Kindergarten in its Bearings on Crime, Pauperism, and Insanity, manuscript copy (Box 10, Folder 35)
    - The Kindergarten in its Bearings on Crime, Pauperism, and Insanity, printed copies (Box 10, Folder 36)
    - The Kindergarten in its Development of Faculty (Box 10, Folder 37)
    - The Kindergarten in its Relation to Industrial Education (Box 8, Folder 54)
    - The Kindergarten in its Relation to Motherhood (Box 8, Folder 55)
    - Women in Education: Their Work in the Kindergarten Department (Box 8, Folder 56)
    - Kindergarten Miscellany (Box 8, Folder 57)
    - Miscellaneous writings on Kindergartens by Sarah Cooper (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - General
    - Education Report for the State of California, prepared by Sarah Cooper, 1871 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Teachers' Institute Address by Mrs. Sarah B. Cooper 1882 (Box 13, Folder 47)
    - Teacher's Association of California, Sixteenth Annual Session, program Dec. 1882 (Box 13, Folder 46)
    - The Education of Girls from a Medical Standpoint, by Edward W. Jenks, M.D., LL.D 1889 (Box 13, Folder 48)
    - Essay in Support of Public Schools (Box 13, Folder 44)
    - National Education Association Address (Box 13, Folder 45)
- Series IV. Women's Organizations
  - General material from Women's Organizations
    - Woman Suffrage Material, 1881, 1917 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Century Club of California, Constitution and By-laws, 1888 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Century Club of California, Fourth Annual Report, 1892 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - The World's Congress Auxiliary of the World's Columbian Exposition, 1893 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - National Council of Women of the United States, Council Catechism, 1894 (Box 13, Folder 29)
    - General Federation of Women's Clubs, meeting minutes, 1894 (Box 10, Folder 48)
    - National Council of Women of the United States, meeting minutes, 1894 (Box 10, Folder 49)
    - General Federation of Women's Clubs, receipts and financial material, 1894-1896 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - The Woman's Congress Association, programs, 1894-1897 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Reminiscences of the Woman's Congress of the Pacific Coast, 1895 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - General Federation of Women's Clubs, Bank book 1896 (Box 13, Folder 31)
    - Woman's Inheritance and Opportunity: Sermon of Reverend Dr. Dille, 1895 (Box 10, Folder 51)
    - Votes for Women, Woman Suffrage Association poster, 1896 (Box 10, Folder 50)
    - General Federation of Women's Clubs, Official Proceedings of the Third Biennial, 1896 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Opening address of The Woman's Congress of the Pacific Coast, 1896 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - The Woman's Congress of the Pacific Coast, Third annual meeting, 1896 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Woman's Congress of 1896, schedule, 1896 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - National Congress of Mothers, program, 1897 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - General Federation of Women's Clubs (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Miscellany (Box 13, Folder 34)
  - Periodicals from Women's Organizations
    - Woman At Work, Mar. 1884 (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - The Woman's Century, Sept. 1884 (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - The Woman's Magazine, Dec. 1884, Sept. 1885-Oct. 1885 (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - The Woman's Magazine, Nov. 1885-Feb. 1886 (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - The Woman's Magazine, July 1886-Sept. 1886; Nov. 1886 (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - Chicago Woman's News, Sept. 1891-Oct. 1891 (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Report, 1893 (Box 13, Folder 33)
    - The Bulletin, 1893 (Box 13, Folder 30)
    - Pages from The New Cycle, 1895 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - The New Cycle, Feb. 1895 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - The New Cycle, Mar. 1895 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - The New Cycle, Apr. 1895 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - The New Cycle, May 1895 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - The Searchlight, June 1895, Sept. 1895, Nov.1895 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - The New Cycle, Sept. 1895 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - The New Cycle, Oct. 1895 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - The New Cycle, Nov. 1895 (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - The New Cycle, Dec. 1895-Jan. 1896 (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - The Pacific Monthly, Mar. 1898 (Box 13, Folder 32)
- Series V. Photographs and Daguerreotypes
  - Daguerreotype of Sarah Cooper, 1850 (Box 9, Folder 47)
  - Photographs of people from Cazenovia, New York - mostly unidentified, 1850-1880 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Daguerreotype of Halsey F. Cooper, 1/16 plate, 1852 (Box 9, Folder 49)
  - Photographs of Sarah Cooper, 1852-1868 (Box 9, Folder 46)
  - Daguerreotype of two unidentified women, 1855 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Photographic reproductions of daguerreotypes of unidentified men, 1855 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Daguerreotype of Sarah Cooper, 1/6 plate, 1855 (Box 9, Folder 42)
  - Ambrotype of Sarah Cooper, 1857 (Box 9, Folder 43)
  - Ambrotype of Sarah Cooper, 1858 (Box 9, Folder 44)
  - Hand Tinted Ambrotype of Harriet Cooper, 1858 (Box 9, Folder 48)
  - Photographs of Harriet Cooper, 1858-1892 (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Ambrotype of Sarah Cooper, 1860 (Box 9, Folder 45)
  - Photographs of Civil War Soldiers, 1860-1865 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Cabinet Cards of Halsey F. Cooper, 1863-1885 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Photograph of Mollie Cooper (Sarah's daughter), 1864 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Cabinet Cards and Cartes de Visite of women - identified, 1864-1885 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Cabinet Cards, Cartes de Visite of Reverend and Mrs. A. Ward Loomis, 1870 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Photograph of Dr. George Boardman, 1870 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Photographs of Los Angeles, 1870-1900 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Cabinet Cards and Cartes de Visite of men - identified, 1870-1900 (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Photographs of Sarah Cooper, 1873-1878 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Photographs of Chinese in California, Sarah Cooper's servant Ah Wong Louie, 1875-1896 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Photograph of the Cooper School, 1880 (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - Photographs of Kindergartens, 1880-1900 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Photographs of Sarah Cooper, 1886-1888 (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - Half Tone Printing Block of Sarah Cooper, 1888 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Photographs of Sarah Cooper, 1890-1896 (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - Photograph of Stanford University, 1891 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Printed and signed photographs of Sarah Cooper from The California Educational Review, 1891 (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - Photograph of Sarah and Harriet Cooper at home, 1893 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Photograph of group, last picture taken of Sarah and Harriet Cooper, Oct. 1896 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Photograph of Cooper Grave, 1897 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Photograph of back door of Sarah Cooper's house in San Francisco, 1896 (Box 9, Folder 50)
  - Photographs of Robert Ingersoll (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Photographs - Miscellaneous (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Photograph of unidentified street corner - possibly Sarah Cooper's street in San Francisco (Box 9, Folder 51)
  - Photograph of County Court House (Box 9, Folder 52)
- Series VI. Clippings
  - Clippings - mostly written by Sarah Cooper, 1850-1859 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Clippings, 1870-1879 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Clippings, 1870-1879 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Clippings, 1880-1889 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Clippings, 1880-1889 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Clippings, 1880-1889 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Clippings - not related to deaths of Sarah and Harriet Cooper, 1890-1899 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Clippings - not related to deaths of Sarah and Harriet Cooper, 1890-1899 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Clippings - not related to deaths of Sarah and Harriet Cooper, 1890-1899 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Clippings - related to Sarah and Harriet Coopers' deaths, 1896 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Clippings - related to Sarah and Harriet Coopers' deaths, 1896 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Clippings - related to Sarah and Harriet Coopers' deaths, 1896 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Clippings, undated (Box 10, Folder 13)
- Series VII. Miscellaneous
  - Psalms in Chinese, given to Harriet Skilton by Ah Wong Louie, 1898 (Box 13, Folder 49)
  - Have You Thought About It?, by Nellie Blessing Eyster, in Chinese (Box 13, Folder 50)
  - The Diamond Palace, advertisement edited by Sarah Cooper (Box 10, Folder 52)